Guide to the Eric Allen Osborne Papers Concerning In Letters of Red
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Eric Allen Osborne papers concerning In letters of red
1935-1938
GEN MSS 512
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(1 box)
The collection consists of letters and manuscripts documenting the publication of the anthology in 1938. Contributors include: W. H. Auden, John Brownson, Cecil Day Lewis, Lion Feuchtwanger, George de Fiedorowicz, Louis Golding, Geoffrey Grigson, Robert Herring, Herbert Hodge, James Lansdale Hodson, Jeffrey Eardley Jeffrey, Peter Lagger, David Low, Louis MacNeice, Kingsley Martin, Siegfried Sassoon, John Strachey, Frank Tilsley, Edward Upward and Rex Warner. Series I, Correspondence, contains letters from 15 of the 20 contributors to Osborne. Letters mention manuscripts, revisions, copyright and book royalties. All letters are accompanied by a typescript summary of the letter contents. Series II, Writings, consists of typescript or printed versions of manuscripts from all contributing writers and biographical statements.
Osborne, E. Allen (Eric Allen), 1906-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased on the Lord fund from Charles A. Stonehill, 1940.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Eric Allen Osborne Papers Concerning In Letters of Red consist of letters and manuscripts documenting the publication of the anthology in 1938. The collection spans the years 1935-38.
The collection is housed in 1 box and organized into two series: Correspondence and Writings.
In Letters of Red was edited by Eric Allen Osborne, author of The Facts about A Christmas Carol (1937), and brings together the work of British poets, novelists, playwrites, scholars, journalists and others in what is described on the book jacket as a "crusade against Fascism." The book included work by both established and emerging authors, at the time of publication, and more than half the material appeared in print for the first time. Authors include: W. H. Auden, John Brownson, Cecil Day Lewis, Lion Feuchtwanger, George de Fiedorowicz, Louis Golding, Geoffrey Grigson, Robert Herring, Herbert Hodge, James Lansdale Hodson, Jeffrey Eardley Jeffrey, Peter Lagger, Louis MacNeice, Kingsley Martin, Siegfried Sassoon, John Strachey, Frank Tilsley, Edward Upward and Rex Warner. There is also a cartoon by David Low.
Series I, Correspondence, consists of correspondence to Osborne from 15 of the 20 contributors. The contributors not represented are Feuchtwanger, Grigson, Hodge, Lagger, and Martin. In most cases correspondence is limited to a single letter and addresses the contribution to the anthology. Letters mention manuscripts, revisions, copyright, and book royalties. All original letters are accompanied by a brief typescript summary of the letter contents.
Series II, Writings, consists of manuscripts from contributing writers. In this case there are roughly an equal number of typescript and printed versions (clippings) for all contributions. There is one holograph poem by Louis MacNeice, and there are holograph and typescript drafts of Osborne's editorial preface. All writings are accompanied by a typescript biographical statement.
Authors, English -- 20th Century; Authors, Irish -- 20th Century; English literature -- 20th Century; Irish literature -- 20th Century; Poets, English -- 20th Century; Poets, Irish -- 20th Century; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973; Brownson, John; Day Lewis, C. (Cecil), 1904-1972; Feuchtwanger, Lion, 1884-1958; Fiedorowicz, Georges de; Golding, Louis, 1895-1958; Grigson, Geoffrey, 1905-1985; Herring, Robert; Hodson, James Lansdale, 1891-1956; Jeffery, Jeffery E. (Jeffery Eardley), 1887-; Low, David, 1891-1963; MacNeice, Louis, 1907-1963; Martin, Kingsley, 1897-1969; Osborne, E. Allen (Eric Allen), 1906-; Sassoon, Siegfried, 1886-1967; Strachey, John, 1901-1963; Tilsley, Frank, 1904-1957; Upward, Edward, 1903-2009; Warner, Rex, 1905-1986
- Correspondence, 1937-38; Series I; 0.21' (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brownson, John, 1938 Feb 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Day Lewis, C. (Cecil), 1937 Oct 30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fiedorowicz, George de, 1938 Feb (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Golding, Louis, 1938 Feb 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Herring, Robert, 1937 Dec 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hodson, James Lansdale, 1937-38 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jeffrey, Jeffrey E. (Jeffrey Eardley), 1938 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Low, David, 1937 Dec 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - MacNeice, Louis, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Marston, Jeffrey
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Jeffrey, Jeffrey E.
  - Sassoon, Siegfried, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Strachey, John, 1937 Nov 30 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Tilsley, Frank, 1937 Dec 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Upward, Edward, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Warner, Rex, 1938 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Writings, 1935-38; Series II; 0.21' (1 box)
  Series II, Writings, is arranged alphabetically by name of author.
  - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh)
    - "Dover," poem, clipping of printed version from New Verse, with editor's annotations, 1937 Nov (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Brownson, John
    - "Women are Fools," story, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Day Lewis, C. (Cecil)
    - "Bombers," poem, clipping from printed version, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Newsreel," poem, typescript, corrected, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "On the Twentieth Anniversary of Soviet Power," poem, clipping of printed version from Russia Today, 1937 Nov (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Feuchtwanger, Lion
    - "Democracy and Dictatorship," chapter, clipping of printed version from Moscow, 1937, corrected (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fiedorowicz, George de
    - "Historical Survey of the Application of Sanctions," essay, typescript and reprint, corrected (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Golding, Louis
    - "Little Heinz from Wismar," story, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Grigson, Geoffrey
    - "In Munich, City of Art," poem, clipping of printed version, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Includes fragment of poem by "K. J. Raine" on verso
  - Herring, Robert
    - "The News-reel," article, clipping of printed version, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Hodge, Herbert
    - "Cannibal Carnival," play, typescript, corrected, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Hodson, James Lansdale
    - "The Way of it," story, typescript, corrected, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Jeffrey, Jeffrey E.
    - "National Hypnotism," article, typescript, corrected, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Lagger, Peter
    - "Epitaph on a Disabled Ex-Serviceman," poem, typescript, corrected and signed (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Includes "Hungry Storm-Trooper's Nightmare"; "Celestial Faux-Pas"; "They shall not Grow Old"; "The Money Trail"; and "Anthropomorphism"
  - MacNeice, Louis
    - "Bagpipe Music," poem, typescript, corrected and signed, with editor's annotations (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - "Salute," poem, holograph, signed, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Includes ALS to Osborne on verso
  - Martin, Kingsley
    - "Thoughts on Spain," essay, typescript, holograph and clippings, corrected, with editor's annotations (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Osborne, E. Allen (Eric Allen)
    - [Editor's preface and frontmatter], holograph and typescript, corrected, [1938?] (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Includes clipping by Sir Peter Chalmers Mitchell
  - Sassoon, Siegfried
    - "Ex-Service," poem, typescript, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "News From the War-After-Next," poem, clipping of printed version, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - "The Ultimate Atrocity," poem, clipping of printed version, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - "An Unveiling," poem, clipping of printed version, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - "The Writing on the Wall," poem, clipping of printed version from The Left Review, with editor's annotatations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Strachey, John
    - "The Education of a Communist," article, clipping of printed version from The Left Review, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Includes poem by "A. L. Morton"
  - Tilsley, Frank
    - "Moore's Act," play, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Upward, Edward
    - "The Island," story, clipping of printed version from The Left Review, with editor's annotations, 1935 Jan (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Warner, Rex
    - "Arms in Spain," poem, clipping of printed version from The Left Review, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Includes Pablo Neruda's "To the Mothers of the Dead Militia" on verso
    - "Jonathan Swift: Defender of Liberty," article, clipping of printed version (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "Visit to a Mine," story, typescript, corrected, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 44)